ILR School Audio-Visual Department Video Cassette Collection /4191 AV
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Cesar Chavez - Revolution of the rural poor - the Delano Grape Strike - April 23, 1967, 13 (Box 34)
- Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers International Union, Local 1, butte Miners, 1955; 14 (Box 34)
  tape of rank and file revolt in 1955
- Wobblies, Part I, 1 (Box 35)
- EAP at your service, 2 (Box 35)
- Biggest Lump of Money in the World, 3 (Box 35)
- Access to Media, 4 (Box 35)
- Corporation After Mr. Sam: Part I-Growth, 5 (Box 35)
  C-19
- Corporation After Mr. Sam: Part III-Succession, 6 (Box 35)
  C-21
- Corporation "After Mr. Sam: Part IV-Decision Making, 7 (Box 35)
  C-22
- Children of Labor (Part II), 8 (Box 35)
  C-6
- Children of Labor (Part I), 9 (Box 35)
  C6
- Contract Contract, Tape I, 5/13/2004, 10 (Box 35)
- Organizational Behavior - Bacharach, 1993; 1 (Box 36)
  Movie Video -- 9/1993
- A H Raskin - Organizing, 2 (Box 36)
  tape #1
- Kruysman Case Study, 1990; 3 (Box 36)
  Edited MASTER -- 2/1990
- The ILR Tape, 4 (Box 36)
- The Struggle to Save Rath Packing, Part II: 7/1986, 5 (Box 36)
- Stanford Seed Company, Small Business Case Study, 1990; 6 (Box 36)
  Edited MASTER -- 1/1990
- Global Assembly Line, 1993; 7 (Box 36)
  Edited Version for G. Boyer -- 9/20/1993
- The Struggle to Save Rath Packing, Part I, 8 (Box 36)
- A Bridge From High School to College; ILR Pre-Freshman: June 1993, 9 (Box 36)
- The Struggle to Save Rath Packing, Part I, 10 (Box 36)
- Prof. W. Whyte - Address to American Sociological Assoc., Part II, 1981, 9 (Box 37)
- Prof. W. Whyte Address to 1981 Amer. Sociological Assoc. Meeting, Part II, 10 (Box 37)
- Whyte Interview by R. Wallace of Hillsdale College, 1981, 11 (Box 37)
- Whyte Interviewed by R. Wallace of Hillsdale College, 1981, 12 (Box 37)
- Prof. W. Whyte Address to American Sociological Assoc., Part I, 1981, 13 (Box 37)
- Prof. W. Whyte Address to 1981 Amer. Sociological Assoc. Meeting, Part I, 14 (Box 37)
- Sidewalk Society, Oct. 8, 1981, 15 (Box 37)
  The North End
- Whyte: 10/18/1980, 16 (Box 37)
- National Association of Arbitrators / Ethics in Arbitration, 17 (Box 37)
- Ethics in Arbitration / California version, 18 (Box 37)
- Sidewalk Society, 1981; 19 (Box 37)
  Weekday! October 8, 1981 -- The North End
- The Early Years, 1 (Box 38)
- Interview with Genene Boldt, Betsey Snyder, 2 (Box 38)
- The Early Years, 3 (Box 38)
- The Early Years, 4 (Box 38)
- The Early Years: History of ILR School, 5 (Box 38)
- The Early Years, 6 (Box 38)
- Alice Cook - ILR 40th Anniversary, 7 (Box 38)
  tape 1 of 4
- Gormley Miller - ILR 40th Anniversary, 8 (Box 38)
- Gormley Miller - ILR 40th Anniversary, 9 (Box 38)
- Alice Cook - ILR 40th Anniversary, 10 (Box 38)
  tape 4 of 4
- 1988 Spring Picnic - 6/2/1988, 1 (Box 39)
- Hot dog Day - 5/17/1989 1990, 2 (Box 39)
- Holiday Lunch - 1992, 3 (Box 39)
- ILR Weight loss - 1988, 4 (Box 39)
- Lipper on Ice - 1989; Bikinis at Flat Rock - 1990; Franks Eggnog - 1990, 5 (Box 39)
- Holiday Party, Seeber Twins, Bobs House, Holiday 1989; Frank Heroy Birthday Bunnie - 10/1990, 6 (Box 39)
- Lisa Diller Bridal Shower - 6/21/1989, 7 (Box 39)
- Elsie Cole Retirement, 8 (Box 39)
- Holiday Luncheon, Pete's Rap - 1991, 9 (Box 39)
- Hot Dog Day - 5/13/1988, 10 (Box 39)
- Lu Lacey Retirement Party, 11 (Box 39)
- Joan Campbell Baby Shower - 3/12/1991, 12 (Box 39)
- Reuben Day - 3/15/1990, 13 (Box 39)
- Taughannock Park - 8/2/1990: ILR Picnic, 14 (Box 39)
- ILR Picnic - 6/28/1990, 15 (Box 39)
- Lippy Hair, 16 (Box 39)
- Summer 1994 - Raw footage, 17 (Box 39)
- Jennie Graham Retirement, 18 (Box 39)
- Shirley Harper Retirement Lunch - 6/29/1993, 19 (Box 39)
- Holiday 1993 - Raw Footage, 20 (Box 39)
- Educom - 1989:10/17/1989, 21 (Box 39)
- Holiday 1993 videos, 22 (Box 39)
- Kay Clark Retirement Party - 3/28/1991; Kim Fellows Baby Shower - 4/16/1991, 23 (Box 39)
- Meeting in Progress, 1 (Box 40)
- Mock Fact Finding Hearing: PERB, 2 (Box 40)
- Mock Fact Finding Hearing: PERB, 3 (Box 40)
- The Lost Work Week, 4 (Box 40)
- Make Performance Matter, 5 (Box 40)
- Managing Your Organizational Reality, 6 (Box 40)
- Kacho: Department Store Manager, 7 (Box 40)
- Job Discrimination (Part II), 8 (Box 40)
- Labor's Turning Point, 9 (Box 40)
- Auzo Lagun: A Woman's Cooperative, 1 (Box 41)
- Ready or Not #8 - Employment (Part II), 2 (Box 41)
- Ready of Not #6 - Housing 8 Living Relationships, 3 (Box 41)
- Reflections - George Meany, 4 (Box 41)
- More than Words, 5 (Box 41)
- The Reckoning, 6 (Box 41)
- Mondragon (BBC), 7 (Box 41)
- Mondragon (BBC), 8 (Box 41)
- Mondragon (Johnson), 9 (Box 41)
- Mondragon, 10 (Box 41)
- Suggestion System in Japanese Corporations, 1 (Box 42)
- Supervisor's Role In: Simplifying the Work Process, 2 (Box 42)
- Tell Me About Yourself, 3 (Box 42)
- We've Always Done It This Way, 4 (Box 42)
- We've Always Done it This Way, 5 (Box 42)
- We Didn't Want It To Happen This Way, 6 (Box 42)
- Telstar Communications: A Case Study, 7 (Box 42)
- Vicki Saporta (Organizing the Unorganized), 8 (Box 42)
- Where Are You? Where Are You Going?, 9 (Box 42)
- America Works, When America Works (Part I), 1 (Box 43)
- American People in WWII, 2 (Box 43)
- New Deal 2, 3 (Box 43)
- New Deal 1, 4 (Box 43)
- Can You Spare a Moment?, 5 (Box 43)
- Changing Situation of Workers Their Unions, 6 (Box 43)
- Like a New Birth: Plant Modernization Through Collective Bargaining, 7 (Box 43)
- America Works / Show 1010C: the New Hungry, 8 (Box 43)
- Japanese Management: Myth and Reality, 1 (Box 44)
- If Japan CanWhy Can't We? (Part II), 2 (Box 44)
- Kyocera Experiment (PBS Enterprise), 3 (Box 44)
- America Works / Show 1008C: Industrial Policy, 4 (Box 44)
- The Detroit Model (Bill Moyer), 5 (Box 44)
- Life of the Western Coal Mine, 6 (Box 44)
- Final Offer - UAW Auto Industry (2), 7 (Box 44)
- Labor Video Bulletin "Expectations", 8 (Box 44)
- N.Y.S. School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Rochester, NY Arbitration Conference, April 13, 1962, 1 (Box 45)
  New Issues in Collective Bargaining -- Afternoon session speakers: Hanslowe (Introduction), Tracey Ferguson, and Richard Lipsitz
- N.Y.S. School of Industrial and Labor Relations, 1962; 2 (Box 45)
  MP Catherwood Management Open House, July 27, 1962
- Konvitz, Milton R., 1960; 3 (Box 45)
  The Open Mind, an NBC TV Broadcast- Dec. 11, 1960
- N.Y.S. School of Industrial and Labor Relations, 1955; 4 (Box 45)
  Tenth Anniversary Dinner, November 18, 1955
- New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations: Extension Division, 1965; 5 (Box 45)
  New York State Teachers Association Conferences - July 7-9, 1965
- New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations: Extension Division, 1965; 6 (Box 45)
- New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations. Extension Division, 1965; 7 (Box 45)
  Alternatives to Crisis Bargaining a one day conference. New York City, December 7, 1965
- New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations. Extension Division, 1965; 8 (Box 45)
  Alternatives to Crisis Bargaining, a one day conference. New York City. December 7, 1965
- New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations. Extension Division, 1965; 9 (Box 45)
- New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations: Extension Division, 1965; 10 (Box 45)
- N.Y.S. School of Industrial and Labor Relations, 1962; 11 (Box 45)
  Dedication, Oct. 2, 1962
- Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers International Union, Local 1, butte Miners, 1955; 12 (Box 45)
  Tape of rank and file revolt in 1955
- New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations: Extension Division, 1965; 13 (Box 45)
  New York State Teachers Association Conference - July 7-9, 1965
- New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations: Extension Division, 1965; 14 (Box 45)
- N.Y.S. School of Industrial and Labor Relations - Dedication, Oct. 2, 1962, 15 (Box 45)
- Shapero #1 (part II) - 4/21/1960, 16 (Box 45)
  #78
- The Best Move I Could Have Made for My Career, 17 (Box 45)
- Sports and Collective Bargaining, 18 (Box 45)
- Interview with Jimmy Hoffa, 1975; 1 (Box 47)
  James Riddle (Jimmy) Hoffa was interviewed at Cornell University's ILR School in April 1975, only 3 months before he disappeared. Hoffa was on campus for a series of meetings and lectures and, according to Professor Cletus Daniel, Hoffa was asked for a filmed interview early that morning but he declined. Throughout the day's meetings and discussions, Daniel continued to talk with Hoffa. During lunch, Daniel told Hoffa that he had been a Teamster, and showed Hoffa his separation card. Seeing that, Hoffa felt more comfortable with the idea of an interview and agreed to it. Because the interview was arranged at the last minute, the best video recording equipment was already in use. As a result, the sound and visual tracks on the original video recording are poor quality.
  - Item 1: Hoffa Interview, 1975; 1; Video file (Box 47)
    Interview of Jimmy Hoffa with Cletus Daniel, Roger R. Keeran, James O. Morris, Robert F. Risley, and Robert R. Julian.
- Labor Relations Cassette of the Month - Feb. 1973 (Box 48)
- Labor Relations Cassette of the Month - Feb. 1973 (Box 49)
- Labor Relations Cassette of the Month - Feb. 1973 (Box 50)
- Labor Relations Cassette of the Month, 1972 (Box 51)
- Labor Relations Cassette of the Month, 1972 (Box 52)
- Basic Labor Law, 1972 (Box 53)
- Basic Labor Law, 1972 (Box 54)
- Labor Relations Cassette of the Month, 1974 (Box 55)
- Labor Relations Cassette of the Month, 1974 (Box 56)
- Labor Relations Cassette of the Month, 1974 (Box 57)
- Labor Relations Cassette of the Month, 1974 (Box 58)
- Labor Relations Cassette of the Month, 1974 (Box 59)
- Labor Relations Cassette of the Month - Nov. 1973 (Box 60)
- Labor Relations Cassette of the Month - Nov. 1973 (Box 61)
- Labor Relations Cassette of the Month - Oct. 1973 (Box 62)
- Labor Relations Cassette of the Month - Apr. 1973 (Box 63)
- Labor Relations Cassette of the Month - Apr. 1973 (Box 64)
- Labor Relations Cassette of the Month - Mar. 1973 (Box 65)
- Labor Relations Cassette of the Month - Mar. 1973 (Box 66)
- Victoria Byerly and Katie Cannon - ILR Press, Ithaca, NY, October 6, 1987 (Box 67)
- Katie Cannon - Oct. 4, 1987 (Box 68)
- Victoria Byerly and Katie Cannon Interview - Property of ILR Press (Box 69)
- Prof. Robert Aronson - "Self-Employment", 1991 (Box 70)
  aired: week of 9/23/1991
- Katie Cannon "Black Women's Literature as Wisdom Lit., 1987 (Box 71)
  Africana Center, Cornell University, ILR Press - October 7, 1987
- Victoria Byerly and Katie Cannon - Hard Times Cotton Mill Girls Reading, 1987 (Box 72)
  GIAC, Ithaca, NY -- October 5, 1987
- Rev. Dr. Katie Geneva Cannon "Black Women's Literature as Wisdom Literature", 1987 (Box 73)
  Africana Center - October 7, 1987
- Victoria Byerly and Katie Cannon - Hard Times Cotton Mill Girls Reading, 1987 (Box 74)
- Victoria Byerly and Katie Cannon: ILR Press, Ithaca, NY, October 6, 1987 (Box 75)
  History as a Source for Critical Consciousness and reading Hard Times Cotton Mill
- Vernon Jensen: 7/13/1989 (Box 76)
- Participant Observation / Prof. W.F. White (Box 77)
- Participant Observation / Prof. W.F. White (Box 78)
- Whyte Impact on an Underdog / Speech by Orlandella (Box 79)
- Whyte Impact on an Underdog / Speech by Orlandella (Box 80)
  Dup MASTER
- William Foote Whyte - Session on participant observ. (Box 81)
- William Foote Whyte - 1976 Session on Participant Observation (Box 82)
  With Kathleen Whyte and Angelo Ralph Orlandella
- Participant Observation / Prof. William F. Whyte (Box 83)
- The Whyte Impact on an Underdog / Ralph Orlandella: October 17, 1980 (Box 84)
- Issues in Seniority / NYSSILR, Richard Block and Arnold Zack (tape 1), 1 (Box 85)
- Issues in Seniority (tape 2), 2 (Box 85)
- The Factfinding Hearing / NYSSILR, Richard Block and Arnold Zack, 1983; 3 (Box 85)
- Problems in Mediation / NYSSILR, Richard Block and Arnold Zack, 1981; 4 (Box 85)
- Cases in Discipline and Discharge / NYSSILR, 5 (Box 85)
- Issues in Arbitrability / NYSSILR, Richard Block and Arnold Zack, 6 (Box 85)